Jack Siler

Creative Director and Designer

San Mateo, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jack-Siler/4a9f13ec4001d6bb

Hands-on creative director who has supervised the development and execution of branding and marketing strategies for established companies and start-ups. Proven leader able to manage and develop the expertise of the in-house creative team and external agencies. Team-oriented and solution-focused approach to problem solving. Extensive experience managing multiple product launches, deadlines and budgets.

Areas of Expertise Include:

- Brand Building Expertise
- Linking Marketing Strategy to Creative Execution
- Production Cycle Management
- Creative Direction Development
- Cross-Functional Collaboration
- In-house Creative & Agency Management
- Product Launch Specialist
- Team Mentoring & Development
- Business Pitch Presentations
- Precise Budget Control

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Creative Director

Virtually Live - December 2015 to February 2017

Managed or designed all creative work for a virtual reality startup specializing in live sporting events. Includes all

branding, video, website, advertising, brochures, UI/UX prototyping, C-level investor presentations and pitch decks.

- Redesigned brand identity to align with business objectives; successfully pitched to executive management and completed full roll out across all marketing and communication channels in 6 weeks.
- Managed the in-house design of all print and digital marketing materials including brand guidelines, advertising,

large-format trade show graphics, digital banners for store and social media, saving \$90,000 per year.

- Managed the redesign of the company website; improved the information architecture, UI/UX and brand alignment.
- Produced and edited live-action and feature videos for consumer, business development and investor needs.
- Designed UI and UX feature storyboards, improving product and development team communications up to 50%.
- Created concept boards for business development team to pitch fully customized, branded VR experiences.
- Designed presentations for C-level, investor relations, industry speeches and business development meetings;

created a standardized and customizable presentation library, increasing sales team efficiency by 3x.

• Developed 90+ presentations per year for new business pitches, financial reviews and content creation for C-level

executives at firms including NASCAR, Formula One, Twitter, Fox Sports, FIFA, and the Premier League.

Director, Creative Services

Sony Computer Entertainment America - San Mateo, CA - October 2013 to September 2015

Led the in-house creative team and external agencies to design and produce all corporate identity and marketing

materials to launch games, systems, peripherals and online services. Includes all branding, printed materials, product

photography, illustration, and renders for packaging, retail POP and activations, PR, promotions and events.

- Directed the visuals for the PlayStation 4 launch, including global branding, product imagery, and sales tools; customized all assets for retail and online, built consensus, drove implementation, managed \$1.2M project budget.
- Directed the design strategy and execution for PlayStation Exclusive partnerships, increasing PlayStation brand

visibility up to 28% across packaging and retail channels.

- Expanded the digital game manual publication to include e-commerce capabilities to sell premium content strategy
- guides, art books, developer diaries, etc.; potential annual revenue of \$2M.
- Managed the in-house creative team and external agency partners to deliver production-ready packaging files for up

to 35 games, 22 accessories and more than 25 console bundles per year for North and South America.

- Wrote and developed brand identity guidelines for platforms and individual products, supporting channel needs.
- Developed large-format tradeshow graphics and provided on-site design support for C-level media presentations.
- Managed a team of 13 creatives, 12 external agencies, 7 production houses, and annual budgets up to \$8.4M. San Mateo, CA 650.759.8317 LinkedIn.com/in/jacksiler jack.siler@comcast.net jacksiler.squarespace.com

PAGE TWO

Senior Manager, Creative Services

Sony Computer Entertainment America - San Mateo, CA - March 2005 to October 2013

Managed the design and key art production of all games, system and accessory packaging, retail POP, tradeshow

graphics and the in-house design teams for North America and creative support for South America. Reorganized the department, establishing a design agency mindset and providing a one-stop, in-house creative resource for Marketing.

• Developed the design strategy and execution of all brand visuals for the PlayStation Move and PlayStation Vita

platform launches in North America across all packaging, product education, promotions and retail channels.

• Championed the transition from print to digital-only game manuals, reducing operational costs \$1.5M per year;

acquired additional responsibilities for all First Party digital game manual production.

- Improved go-to-market processes for packaging and retail POP execution by developing communication tools and production calendars for all stakeholders and increasing collaboration between departments.
- Directed retailer campaigns for up to 20 ongoing programs across 10 national accounts for PlayStation products.
- Reduced design cycles for retail and online needs by creating tailored campaign "tool boxes" for marketing teams.
- Developed 3 staff from individual contributors to people managers through individualized coaching and training.

Creative Services Manager

- February 2000 to March 2005

Managed the North American design and production of half of PlayStation's games, all of the printed materials and the development of brand guidelines. Managed 2 direct reports. Achieved promotion of 1 staff to Associate Product Manager.

Creative Services Manager

Russell-Welsh - July 1999 to October 1999

Developed communication tools supporting client objectives as production manager and in-house designer. Managed

vendor and designer schedules. Managed 1 direct report.

Senior Marketing Communication Specialist

Emery Worldwide - June 1996 to July 1999

In-house designer creating or managing the design of sales materials and communications tools supporting product

launches, regional advertising, brochures and other sales tools.

Marketing Analyst

Manpower International Inc - January 1993 to February 1996

Supported the establishment of Manpower's European headquarters with a focus on developing relationships with Fortune 500 accounts. Member of an international staff of 5.

Customer Support Assistant

Xerox Corporation - October 1988 to December 1992

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Marketing

Pace University - New York, NY 1992

SKILLS

Creative Suite (7 years), Microsoft Office (10+ years), Creative Direction (10+ years), Graphic Design (10+ years), Vendor Management (10+ years), Collaboration (10+ years), Collateral Development (10+ years), Presentation Design (10+ years), Presentation Skills (10+ years), Budget Management (10+ years), Branding (10+ years), Brand Development (10+ years)

LINKS

http://www.jacksiler.squarespace.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacksiler/

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Freelance:

Vela Finance | Startup marketing materials and front-end web redesign. 2017

Powers Squared | Logo design. 2017 Foster City Little League | Logo design and marketing material. 2016 – 2017

Volunteer:

San Mateo Youth Softball Association | League Photographer 2013 – Present